Hoffman Family Papers
© 2006 University of Connecticut
- Series IV: Government Documents, undated, 1965-1980
  - Government, 1971 (4), [1. San Francisco FBI to Director FBI, Los Angeles FBI, San Diego FBI, New York City FBI, Hoffman met with his lawyer Michael Kennedy, said he is hot and will avoid meetings with people; 2. Chicago FBI to Director FBI, transcript from appearance on Howard Miller Show; 3. unidentified agent or agency, short article on Hoffman; 4. New York City FBI, biography, business deals with Steal This Book; 5. Director FBI to Chicago FBI, Cleveland FBI, Los Angeles FBI, New York City FBI, Salt Lake City FBI, San Francisco FBI, Washington Field Office FBI, Attorney General requests surveillance of Hoffman; 6. Chicago FBI, appearance on Kup's Show; 7. Washington Field Office FBI to Director FBI, New York City FBI, Chicago FBI, Hoffman posts bail for inter-state riot charges; 8. New York City FBI, Rubin turns himself in for charge stemming from Washington, DC protests; 9. New York City FBI, Anita Hoffman statement; 10. New York City FBI to Director FBI, document black-out; 11. Oklahoma City FBI, travel plans for Washington, DC; 12. New York City FBI to Director FBI, San Francisco FBI, Washington Field Office, administrative concerns; 13. Washington, DC Field Office to Director FBI, Chicago FBI, New York City FBI, trial proceedings for inter-state riot case; 14. Director FBI to Washington, DC Field Office, travel plans to Washington, DC; 15. Legat Ottawa to Director FBI, cover sheet; 16. Washington, DC Field Office, investigation of hotel location; 17. New York City FBI, transcript form appearance on Free Time; 18. New York City FBI, biography with notes from appearance on Free Time and at Florida State University, news article - Time Magazine Chicago 7 reunion; 19. Washington, DC Field Office, report on bail from New York City FBI; 20. Chicago FBI to Director for New York City FBI, San Juan FBI, Legat Caracas, Legat London, and Legat Paris, travel information in Virgin Islands; 21. Chicago FBI, news article - Time Magazine Bobby Seale's birthday; 22. Chicago FBI, San Juan FBI, New York FBI, information on travel in Virgin Islands] (Box 7:153)
  - Government, 1971 (5), [1. unidentified agent or agency, speech in Oklahoma in violation of anti-riot statute; 2. New York City FBI, biography, news article - East Village Other on Steal This Book; 3. unidentified agent or agency to United States Attorney Washington, DC, May Day demonstration; 4. Washington, DC Field Office FBI, cover sheet denotes investigations in New Orleans, New York City, San Francisco, Washington, DC Field Office, and a Department of Justice request; 5. New York City FBI to Director FBI, news article - East Village Other on Revolution for the Hell of It; 6. A.W. Gray to E.S. Miller, some surveillance prior to and during May Day demonstration was illegal; 7. Washington, DC Field Office FBI, interview with doctor who treated Hoffman; 8. Washington, DC Field Office FBI, charge against Hoffman; 9. Washington, DC Field Office FBI, trying to establish Hoffman was actually arrested during the Washington, DC demonstration; 10. Washington, DC Field Office FBI, one interview at construction site, three interviews at typewriter company, one interview at auto dealership, one interview with resident; 11. New York City FBI, interview with Time Magazine photographer for unpublished photographs; 12. Washington, DC Field Office FBI, advising on arraignment of Hoffman; 13. New York City FBI, news article - East Village Other appeal for Hoffman's innocence; 14. Legat London to Director FBI, Hoffman to London, report of behavior on flight; 15. Director FBI, Hoover rejects Iowa State University's request for information regarding Hoffman; 16. Washington, DC Field Office FBI, Iowa State visit cancelled; 17. unidentified agent or agency, Hoffman charged with contempt of court in the Dellinger et. al. case for violating travel restrictions; 18. Legat London to Director FBI, Hoffman in Northern Ireland; 19. New York City FBI, Rubin and Ellsburg found guilty in inter-state riot case; 20. New York City FBI, notes on speech at Drew University; 21. Legat Paris to Director FBI, black-out; 22. Legat London to Director FBI, black-out; 23. New York Secret Service, basic biography with focus on Free Time appearance and Florida State University] (Box 7:154)
  - Government, 1972, [1. San Juan FBI to Director FBI, Hoffman travel in Virgin Islands; 2. unidentified agent or agency, article on Hoffman in St. Thomas Daily News; 3. Oklahoma City FBI, wiretap at Oklahoma University appearance, clip and United States Attorney in Oklahoma; 4. New York City FBI, documents concerning demonstration at Democratic and Republican National Conventions in Miami Beach, arrest record; 5. New York City FBI, biography with YIP section; 6. Chicago FBI to Director FBI, notes on speech at Marshall University; 7. Washington, DC Field Office FBI, charges dismissed in inter-state riot case; 8. New York City FBI, Hoffman on Today Show about Democratic and Republican National Conventions] (Box 7:155)
  - Government, 1973, [1. unidentified agent or agency, impeachment hearings record from Congressional Record; 2. Shakelford to Miller, Hoffman arrested on cocaine charges; 3. New York City FBI to Director FBI, bail issues, Hoffman released; 4. Pittsburg FBI to Director FBI, records of Robert E. Hinerman of West Virginia; 5. New York City FBI, cocaine charges with brief biography of Hoffman; 6. Director FBI, letter from individual concerning Steal This Book, FBI response; 7. unidentified agent or agency, letter for Hoffman in WIN Magazine; 8. New York City FBI to Director FBI, report on cocaine charges; 9. unidentified agent or agency, New York Magistrate, court documents; 10. Chicago FBI, Hoffman has contempt of court charges from Dellinger et. al. thrown out by Judge Gignoux; 11. Drug Enforcement Administration to New York City FBI, request for Hoffman's full arrest record; 12. news article - New York Times, Hoffman declared a fugitive; 13. Director FBI to Legat Mexico City, information concerning Hoffman, New York City FBI to Director FBI and Boston FBI, information concerning Hoffman] (Box 7:156)
  - Government, 1974, [1. New York City FBI to Director FBI, Hoffman biography; 2. New York City FBI, surveillance on Anita Hoffman; 3. New York City FBI. transcript of appearance on Dick Cavett Show; 4. Director FBI, surveillance not leading to any new information; 5. New York City FBI to Springfield FBI, information on Stravinsky; 6. New York City FBI to Chicago FBI, Chicago to investigate Hoffman's whereabouts; 7. New York City FBI to Director FBI, information on Swerdloff and surveillance on associates; 8. Mexico City Legat to Director FBI and Director FBI to Boston FBI and New York City FBI, black-out; 9. news article - New York Post, Hoffman seeks dismissal of charges; 10. New York City FBI to Director FBI, Hoffman receives no inheritance after father's death; 11. unidentified agent or agency, arrest warrant for Hoffman; 12. Miami FBI to New York City FBI, in-law Kushner does not provide information; 13. San Juan FBI to New York City FBI, investigate John Smith in St. Thomas; 14. Boston FBI to New York City FBI, interview with Jack Hoffman yields no results, New York City FBI, report on family; 15. New York City FBI to Director FBI, Ramer, co-defendant in case, is re-captured; 16. New York City FBI, summary of case, Hoffman severes ties with YIP, investigation of co-defendants and surveillance of Anita Hoffman; 17. New York City FBI, tips on Hoffman, surveillance of Anita Hoffman; 18. El Paso FBI to Miami FBI, Pittsburg FBI, and Director FBI, Hoffman involved in conspiracy to kill the president; 19. New York City FBI to Director FBI, no prosecution in cocaine case until FBI comes forward with wire-tapping information; 20. Boston FBI to New York City FBI and Director FBI, questions regarding Mexico; 21. New York City FBI to Director FBI, Alexandria FBI, Chicago FBI, Detroit FBI, Houston FBI, Norfolk FBI, San Antonio FBI, Washington, DC Field Office FBI, Boston FBI, Dallas FBI, El Paso FBI, Miami FBI, Richmond FBI, and San Juan FBI, information concerning prior arrest on plane and biography] (Box 7:157)
  - Government, 1975, [1. New York City FBI, Hoffman refers to Holbrook in article, begin investigation; 2. New York City FBI, Hoffman sends hand-written request for his FBI file; 3. New York City FBI, news articles from underground press with interviews with Hoffman; 4. Boston FBI to New York City FBI, notes on family interviews; 5. San Francisco FBI to ADIC, New York, sightings in San Francisco; 6. New York City FBI to San Antonio, investigation leads to Jeff Shero; 7. New York City FBI to Newark FBI, basic charges in cocaine case; 8. New York City FBI, arrest of William Jacob Hoffman, no connection; 9. Boston FBI to New York City FBI, discussion of inheritance from father; 10. Boston FBI to New York City FBI, surveillance of Reshick; 11. New York City FBI to Director FBI, news articles "What Makes Abbie Run?", "On Board the Underground Railroad", "Behind the Scenes", Weather Underground; 12. New York City FBI to Miami FBI and Newark FBI, black-out; 13. New York City FBI to Boston FBI, tactics for investigation; 14. New York City FBI to Miami FBI, photographs of Hoffman; 15. unidentified agent or agency, Hoffman's arrest record; 16. unidentified agent or agency, biography and fingerprints; 17. San Francisco FBI to New York City FBI, no information on Ellsburg or Reznick, San Francisco FBI, Los Angeles FBI and Jacksonville FBI follow leads; 18. New Haven FBI to New York City FBI, investigation of Cummings; 19. Albany FBI to Director FBI, lead points to Total Loss Farm in Brattleboro, VT] (Box 7:158)
  - Government, 1976, [1. unidentified agent or agency, Rubin letter to Hoffman in New York Times Magazine; 2. New York City FBI, investigate Drosnin; 3. unidentified agent or agency, interviews at airports, rental car outlets, and Holiday Inns throughout Texas looking for an individual who asked for "Cousin Chuck"; 4. San Francisco FBI to ADIC, New York, investigate Kelley; 5. Los Angeles FBI to New York City FBI, no leads in San Francisco; 6. New York City FBI, investigate Peterson, Clark, and Kushner; 7. Farrington to McDermott, Hoffman letter to FBI printed in New York Times; 8. news article - New York Post, Rubin "Growing Up"; 9. New York City FBI, Anita Hoffman interviewed; 10. Director FBI to New York City FBI, suit against NYCPD for illegal surveillance; 11. San Antonio to New York City FBI, Jack Hoffman lead in Mexico; 12. Director FBI to New York City FBI, COINTELPRO papers released; 13. Dallas FBI to New York City FBI and Chicago FBI to New York City FBI and Houston FBI to New York City FBI, Hoffman interview in Playboy Magazine; 14. Las Vegas FBI to Director FBI and New York City FBI, Crosetti does not yield a lead; 15. New York City FBI, Smith and Camila interviewed; 16. New Orleans to Director FBI, leads in Louisiana yield no information] (Box 7:159)
  - Government, 1977, [1. Director FBI to ADIC, New York, no grand jury probe for publishers involved in Hoffman interviews; 2. ADIC, New York to Director FBI, requests publisher information for those involved in Hoffman interviews; 3. ADIC, New York to Director FBI, Hoffman takes tour of FBI Building and publishes report in Penthouse; 4. New York City FBI, surveillance at Stanley Segal Show; 5. New York City FBI, biography of Hoffman] (Box 7:160)
  - Government, 1978, [1. Los Angeles FBI to ADIC, New York, Hoffman in movie according to the Los Angeles Examiner, summary of interview; 2. unidentified agent or agency, Buffalo Tribe, Earth Day with flyer and information on pot legalization; 3. Buffalo FBI to New York City FBI, Hoffman advertised at Earth Day event but does not appear; 4. New York City FBI, investigate claims of fight with Hoffman, proves false; 5. Boston FBI to New York City FBI, Worchester PD wants picture of Hoffman; 6. New York City FBI, Hoffman is the travel editor of Crawdaddy Magazine, moves to contact Jack Hoffman; 7. Boston FBI to New York City FBI, Hoffman has not contacted Jack Hoffman; 8. unidentified agent or agency to ADIC, New York, Drosnin writing book, CBS documentary called "Days of Rage," seek to find if Hoffman is participating; 9. New York City FBI, rally by YIP for Hoffman in New York Post was a ploy; 10. Boston FBI to New York City FBI, arrest of an individual who looks like Hoffman; 11. unidentified agent or agency, photographs of Hoffman and other that have been investigated] (Box 7:161)
  - Government, 1979, [1. New York City FBI to Knoxville FBI, look for Hoffman in Sneedsville, Knoxville finds no productive leads; 2. unidentified agent or agency, Hoffman on Chris Stanley news article; 3. Newark FBI to ADIC, New York, Trantino in prison in New Jersey; 4. New York City FBI, interview O'Donoghue, Reichback, and Fenton about a party for Hoffman, Reichback reports that Hoffman may turn himself in; 5. New York City FBI, interview Selz, Markson, Masterson about movie deal] (Box 7:162)
  - Government, 1980, [1. unidentified agent or agency, Assistant United States Attorney Fitzpatrick dismisses Unlawful Flight to Avoid Prosecution charges; 2. New York City FBI to Albany FBI and Ottawa Legat, Hoffman to be interviewed by Barbara Walters, no need to arrest because Hoffman will turn himself in on 9-14-80, Hoffman biography and "Save the River" information] (Box 7:163)
- Series V: Newspaper and Periodical Clippings, undated, 1936-1997
  - News, undated, [1. Deborah Rankin, "Some Common Mistakes, Old and New," unknown, filing tax returns; 2. Associated Press, "Drug tests by NCAA overruled," unknown, judge rejects NCAA policy on drug testing; 3. Philip Shenon, "Meese Says U.S. Will Support Drug Tests for New Teachers," New York Times, Attorney General Edward Meese supports mandatory drug tests for teachers; 4. unknown, "Eat Your Way to Youth and Vitality," Examiner, power foods to keep you young; 5. uknown, picture of Hoffman from 1961 when he was the manager of Park Arts Theater in Worcester, MA, unknown, context unknown; 6. Bob Greene; "And Now, Here's… Abbie," unknown, production staring Hoffman based on his book To America With Love; 7. Rory O'Connor, "(illegible) picks Hoffman's nose," The Soho News, illegal survellience during the 1971 May Day demonstrations; 8. unknown, unknown, unknown, short piece on cocaine charges and previous marriage to Anita; 10. unknown, "They still love Jane and Abbie," unknown, short article on the results of the book Woodstock Census: Nationwide Survey of the '60s Generation; 11. Stew Albert, "God Bless America," Crawdaddy, personal reflections on Anita and America following an event; 12. unknown, "Hill-Spencer exchange vows," unknown, Kathryn Marie Hill and Kyle Earl Spencer are married; 13. Mike Royko, "Thou shalt not deprive thy banker," unknown, discusses televanglist Jimmy Swaggart; 14. unknown, "Passover Recipe," uknown, Russian Borscht; 15. Associated Press, "Enzyme Therapy Urged In Heart Attack Cases," unkown, enzyme therapy findings; 16. unknown, "Hahnemann Curbs Use Of Solution," unknown, Worcester hospital no longer uses hexachlorophene for washing babies; 17. Associated Press, "Judge refuses to bar FAA worker drug tests," unknown, FAA employees continue to be drug tested; 18. unknown, "Views on rich are world apart," USA Today, pie chart of survey on views of sources of wealth; 19. Sam Meddis, "Jury's still out on FBI surveillance," USA Today, legality of FBI surveillance; 20. Sally Ann Stewart, "LSD pops back on the scene," USA Today, LSD usage statistics on the rise; 21. unknown, "FAA stops doing own drug tests," USA Today, FAA stops their drug tests; 22. Howard W. French, "Battling Drug Use on the Job," New York Times, how companies combat drug use; 23. unknown, "Truckers' test: 30‰ took drugs," USA Today, drug usage amongst truckers; 24. unknown, "New York City Plans Drug Test In Felony Cases," New York Times, New York City plans for drug test program; 25. Scott Smith; "GW opts to teach rather than test," unknown, George Washington education based anti-drug program; 26. Sandra Sugawara, "Pentagon contractors expect closer scrutiny," unknown, more oversight on Pentagon contracts; 27. Associated Press, "Contract for billions in probe," unknown, investigation in Pentagon contracts; 28. Associated Press, "Meese calls for drug test on suspect's arrest," unknown, Meese wants all people arrested subject to drug tests; 29. Philip Shabecoff, "U.S. Bars Proposal to Limit Acid Rain," New York Times, no agreement on limiting flow of nitrogen oxide pollutant to Canada; 30. Paul Della Valle, "Two words say it all: Jack Tubert," unknown, article on columnist Jack Tubert; 31. Mike Zielinski, "FBI's probe of CISPES exposed," Guardian, FBI surveillance on CISPES; 32. John C. Agnew, "Fr. Gilgun Heads a Unique Community," unknown, Rev. Gilgun experimental community outside of Worcester; 33. N.K. Fields, n/a, unknown, letter to the editor claims Hoffman worked for the government; 34. unknown, unknown, unknown, harmful affects of DDT; 35. Arthur Levin, "Ultimate Specialists: Six fo the Best Doctors In the World," unknown, profile of famous doctors; 36. Edward Kenney, "Alpha Relaxation Techniques for Self-Improvement," unknown, relaxation techniques; 37. Abbie Hoffman, "Abbie Hoffman tenders resignation from the movement," unknown, "retirement letter" from the Movement; 38. Lee M. Hammel, "Prospect House to Give Abbie Hoffman Plaque," unknown, Hoffman recognized by organization.] (Box 8:164)
  - News, 1936, [n/a, n/a, New York Times, front page of Monday November 30th 1936 paper.] (Box 8:165)
  - News, 1939, [. n/a, n/a, Worcester Telegram, front page of Wednesday September 13th 1939 paper.] (Box 8:166)
  - News, 1945, [unknown, n/a, unknown, picture of Phyllis Hoffman at four years old with the caption "Waiting for Doom's Day".] (Box 8:167)
  - News, 1953, [n/a, n/a, The Morning Gazette (Worcester), front page of Wednesday June 10th 1953 with coverage of tornado in Western Massachusetts.] (Box 8:168)
  - News, 1959, [. n/a, "Susan Sandman and Abbott Hoffman Candidates for Brandeis Degrees," unknown, profile of Hoffman just prior to graduation (two copies).] (Box 8:169)
  - News, 1961, [Margaret Lincoln, "Art Films Psychologist's Hobby," Worcester Telegram, interview with Hoffman concerning his love of film (original with two copies).] (Box 8:170)
  - News, 1963, [n/a, n/a, The Evening Gazette (Worcester), front page of Friday November 22nd 1963 with coverage of the assassination of John F. Kennedy; 2. The Evening Gazette (Worcester), Saturday November 23rd 1963.] (Box 8:171)
  - News, 1966, [1. Abbie Hoffman, "SNCC: The Desecration Of a Delayed Dream," Village Voice, Hoffman denounces SNCC for their ideological shift; 2. Abbie Hoffman, "Another Look At the Movement," Village Voice, Hoffman further denounces SNCC and discusses the negative reaction he received.] (Box 8:172)
  - News, 1967, [1. Abbott Hoffman, "View From Canal 11th" and "Vencermos!", The Punch, poetry (two copies); 2. Abbott Hoffman, "Hallucinations from the Real World," The Punch, description of Be-In at Central Park on Easter.] (Box 8:173)
  - News, 1968, [1. unknown, "Yippie Leader (illegible)," unknown, analysis of Hoffman's activities at the Democratic National Convention; 2. unknown, "Ex-City Man Leads Yippies in Chicago," unknown, report of Hoffman's activities at the Democratic National Convention; 3. Walter Bowart, "Casting the Money Throwers From the Temple," unknown, Hoffman throws money onto the Stock Market floor; 4. James A. Gourgouras, "Heartache Real For Hoffmans," Worcester Telegram, feelings of family during and after Democratic National Convention (original with one copy); 5. unknown, unknown, unknown, Bishop James Pike explains what a Hippie is; 6. Abbie Hoffman, n/a, The Punch, letter to the editor asking for excerpts from Revolution for the Hell of It to be printed in the paper; 7. Associated Press, "Abbie Hoffman, Wife Arrested at Hearing," unknown; Hoffman arrested at a anti-HUAC demonstration; 8. Daniel Greene, "As Yippies Bait System 'It's All a Myth, Man'," National Observer, Hoffman, Rubin, and the Yippie movement; 9. Raymod P. Girard, "Brother Defends Abbie's Positions," unknown, Jack Hoffman defends Hoffman's actions in Chicago; 10. unknown, "Yippie! Was Here," unknown, Hoffman appearance at book signing; 11. Associated Press, "Yippies Make Scene At Capital Hearings," uknown, anti-HUAC demonstration during hearings; 12. Frank Dudock, "Hoffman's Book," The Punch, discussion of Revolution for the Hell of It and Yippies.] (Box 8:174)